The rosmsg info command prints out message type information to the console.
Rosmsg info 命令在控制台上打印出消息类型
Let's get more information about the cmd_vel topic.
我们进一步了解一下 cmd_vel 主题
First, I am going to clear the terminal,
首先 我会清空终端
and then I am going to use the command rosmsg show
然后 我会使用 rosmsg show 命令
and then the name of the package containing the message type.
然后是包括消息类型的包的名称
In this case, it's geometry_msgs/Twist as we saw a moment ago,
在这里 名称为 geometry_msgs/Twist 我们刚刚见过
forward slash and finally twist,
斜线 然后输入 twist
the name of the message type and there we have it.
这样 我们就完成了消息类型的名称
The full message definition for the twist type.
Twist 类型的完整消息定义
You can see from the command output that the twist message
根据命令输入 你可以看到 twist 消息
is composed of two messages of type vector three.
由两条消息组成 类型为向量 3
A type that is also defined in the geometry messages package.
这也是几何消息包中定义的类型
There's one three dimensional vector for linear velocity and one for angular velocity.
有一个三维向量 表示线性速度 还有一个表示角速度
Each vector consists of three different 64 bit floating point components, component x,
每个向量都由三个不同的 64 位浮点分量组成：分量 x
y and z. Float64 is one of the built
y 和 z Float64 是一个内置
in primitive data types available to you in creating custom messages.
的原始数据类型 你可以在创建定制消息时使用
To get more information about the built in types and message definitions in general,
要获得内置类型和消息定义的更多信息
check out the links in the text module accompanying the screencast.
请检查和截屏相关的文本模块里的链接
While ros message info is a very useful tool for getting information about messages,
尽管 ROS 消息工具对了解消息内容非常有用
it does not tell us everything we may wish to know.
它并不能提供所有相关信息
Another tool at your disposal is rosed.
你还可以利用另一个工具 rosed
Rosed is a simple bash command that allows you to
Rosed 是一个简单的 bash 命令 利用它
easily view and edit files in your ros environment.
你可以在 ROS 环境中轻松查看并编辑文件
Let's use it to view the twist message definition.
我们用它来查看 twist 消息定义
Once again I'm going to clear this terminal and then I'm going to
同样地 我清空终端 然后执行
execute the command rosed followed by geometry
命令 rosed 后面是 geometry
underscore messages the name of the package containing the message in
下划线 messages 包括有问题的消息的包的名称
question followed by twist.msg,
然后是 twist.msg
the name of the message definition you wish to open.
你想打开的消息定义的名称
Note, that if you've forgotten either the package name or the name of the message type,
注意 如果你忘记了包的名称或消息类型名称
tab completion will come to the rescue.
可以按 Tab 完成
All right here we go. It's the actual message definition.
好的 可以了 这是实际的消息定义
It looks very similar to the output we saw from the rosmessage info command.
它看起来非常像我们看到的 rosmessage info 命令的输出
Except there are a couple of important differences.
但是有几个重要的不同
The first thing you might notice is that there are
你首先会注意到的是
no details about how each vector 3 message is defined.
它没有说明具体如何定义每个 vector 3 消息
This detail is elsewhere,
具体信息在别的地方
particularly within the vector 3.msg file also living within this package.
它在 vector 3.msg 文件里 也在这个包中
The rosmessage info command was simply doing us
Rosmessage info 命令只是顺带
the favor of expanding the definitions in the console output.
在控制台输出中提供完整的定义
The second thing you might notice are the comments.
你会注意到的第二点 是注释
This is the true reason that we came here.
这是我们真正要关注的
When in doubt go to the source code.
碰到疑问时 要查看源代码
Rosmessage info didn't tell us anything about
Rosmessage info 并没有提供
how the twist message is actually intended to be used.
任何关于 twist 消息如何使用的方法
But the friendly ros developer who created this message has our back.
但这位 ROS 开发者非常友好 他创建了这条消息 帮了我们大忙
Most of the message type definitions that are part of
标准的 ROS 分支中所包括的大部分
the standard ros distribution have a wealth of
消息类型定义都有大量
comments explaining how they are meant to be used.
注释 解释了具体用法
Here you can see that the twist messages are actually intended
在这里 你可以看到 twist 消息实际上用于
to contain linear and angular velocity vectors.
包含线性速度和角速度向量
This is something that might have been clear from the usage,
在使用过程中 我们会掌握这一点
after all we saw that these messages were being passed around on the cmd_vel topic,
因为我们可以看到 消息正在围绕 cmd_vel 主题传递
but it was not something that was clear from looking at
但如果只看 rosmsg show 命令
the output of the rosmsg show command.
的输出 这一点并不清晰
Once again, when in doubt check the source code.
同样地 碰到疑问时 查看源代码
This will be a common theme in ros development.
这会是 ROS 开发中的通用做法